Turn to your neigbour and greet them, "Good Morning".
Give your neighbour a handshake and say, "Good Morning!"
Give your other neighbour a handshake and say, "Good Morning!"
Give the neighbour behind you a handshake and say, "Good Morning!"
Give the neighbour in front of you a handshake and say, "Good Morning!"
and greet the viewers all over the world on Emmanuel TV, "Good Morning!"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Yes, you may have your seats in the presence of God.
Wow! Thank You, Jesus, for the wonderful grace to be here.
Just before delving into today's message,
I want to make one thing very clear;
whatever you will hear from me today and whatever you will see in my life today
is as a direct result of the amazing grace of God in the life of Prophet T.B. Joshua.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
At a time where selfishness reigns supreme and materialism runs rife,
it's so rare and precious to see someone who so selflessly, sacrificially gives his time,
love, resources, energy, his whole life to the advancement of God's Kingdom
and to the development of others.
Prophet T.B. Joshua is not a man seeking fame or fortune, wealth or material positions - no!
He is a man after God's own heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You and I know that this ministry, we could have branches in every country all over the world.
People are demanding it.
We could build a cathedral that could seat the largest, highest number of people.
But Prophet T.B. Joshua knows that these are not the things that are tests to our genuineness.
These are not the strengths of the ministry.
The strength of the ministry is the Holy Spirit.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You heard the instructions from God.
Even now, Prophet T.B. Joshua is removing the overflow congregation
because obedience is better than sacrifice.
He is not interested in building structures; he is interested in building people.
He is not concerned about populating this church but populating the Kingdom of God - Heaven.
Thank You, Jesus Christ.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Today I want to ask you a question.
This is a question that I believe may have run through your mind before
and it's a very important issue that we need to talk to ourselves as children of God,
to examine ourselves in the light of God's Word.
Why is it that so often, we repeat our wrong,
we return to our mistakes even after we have seen the repercussions?
I mean, just examine your life.
You know the price you pay anytime you misbehave.
You know the damage that is done -
damage that is done to you heart, relationships, business, career, destiny, just name it
Anytime you misbehave, you know what happens.
Yet, time and time again, we seem to so easily fall into the trap of satan.
We easily fall for satan's tricks;
we are so easily enticed, ensnared and entrapped.
Like Prophet T.B. Joshua said:
We just see the outward effects of the devil but we seem to be blind to the spiritual cause.
We are concerned with the fruits; we look at the fruits instead of striking the root.
This is what I want to talk about today and I just want to share a very quick story.
This is a true story, a real life experience that happened.
It was here in the church. I remember it very vividly.
We were doing a time of counselling on Monday for those that received healing and deliverance.
A young man came to where the evangelists were and he was crying his eyes out.
He was distraught, distressed.
His tears could evoke sympathy from even the stoniest of hearts.
If you saw the way this guy was crying, wailing, moaning, grumbling…
In the midst of this, we were trying to find out what was happening, what was going on.
Long story short, we were able to decipher through the pain, the tears and the cries
that this young man was a happily married man, two children, great job, picture-perfect life
when suddenly something happened.
One day, he received a friend request on Facebook from a lady he did not know and he just accepted.
One thing led to another - discussions started, exchange of words, conversations, pictures.
Later, he went to go and meet that very same lady.
And before he knew it, sin had entered.
Unknown to him, that lady attended the same college as his wife.
Through a mutual friend, the secret was leaked, and the wife took away the children and left home.
This man was distraught, crying.
He made one statement, "Satan sent this Jezebel, Delilah to come and destroy my marriage“.
But we tried to probe and go deep to the root of the issue.
We asked the brother a question, "Brother, who accepted the friend request?"
He said, "It was me".
"Who initiated the conversation with this lady?"
"Me."
"Who asked for her picture?"
"Who suggested that you meet up and arranged a meeting with her?"
"Me."
"Who put a password on your phone so that your wife will not suspect what is going on?"
"No Delilah destroyed your marriage. You tempted the devil to tempt you."
The SCOAN Sunday Service
By the grace of God, in this particular instance, God used Prophet T.B. Joshua to call the wife.
She came and after many tears, there was forgiveness and the couple was reconciled together.
Glory be to God.
But the story does not end here.
Six months later thereabout, I was holding one of the Emmanuel TV prayerlines and the phone rang.
The voice of the person at the other end sounded familiar.
The brother said, "Please, help me, pray for me. My wife has left".
I began to know, "Wait a minute. This is the same guy!"
I asked him a question and his name and I knew it was the same guy.
The moment he realised that I knew what had happened, he grew silent.
And I asked him, "Brother, what happened again? The issue was resolved".
He was silent.
Until finally, he said, "I met another lady on Facebook".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
People of God, I don't want you to judge that young man
and I am not here to judge him because no one is perfect.
I want you to examine your own life.
Those healed of the punishment of sin are likely to return to sin when the pains are over.
We all fight these battles.
The battle we fight in our daily walk is with our flesh, our senses.
By nature, man is rebellious.
Man's spirit - if we choose, we would likely choose fleshly desires,
and satan is looking for any opportunity to strike, to hit,
to get in and corrupt, and get into our heart.
He is looking for that chance.
Anytime you succumb to temptations, fleshly desires, fleshly tendencies,
satan has a foothold in your heart.
He gets in, starts his work of stealing, killing destruction, injecting his poison.
He gets busy at work, eroding your morals, dulling your conscience,
decaying your values, blurring the lines between the acceptable and abominable.
Before you know it, satan with a foothold in your heart,
something you vowed that you would never do, suddenly you think,
"Maybe, I should just try it once. Maybe it wouldn’t be so bad".
Something that you have eaten before and it was bitter, disgusting, destructive.
You say, "Maybe if I try it this time, there will be a different result. Let me still try it".
Something that as a child, you were told, "Don’t go there! Don’t do this; this will destroy you!",
you say, "Well, maybe they didn’t know. Maybe there is a reason why they told me not to go there.
Let me just try it out and see for myself. Experience is the best teacher".
Black and white fade to grey.
People of God know this.
When the Word of God is in your heart, it will preserve and protect you from desiring sin.
Tell your neighbour.
This brings us to the title of today's message: DEALING WITH DESIRE.
Turn with me in your Bible to the proof text which is taken from the Book of James 1:13 - 15.
We need to deal with desire because prevention is better than cure.
James 1:13-15:
"When tempted, no one should say, God is tempting me.
For God cannot be tempted by evil, nor does He tempt anyone;
but each person is tempted when they are dragged away
by their own evil desire and enticed.
Then, after desire has conceived, it gives birth to sin
and sin, when it is full-grown, gives birth to death."
Everyone has fleshly desires but do you provide a platform for them in your heart?
Do you lay a foundation for them to flourish,
a base for them to bloom in your heart?
One thing I want to let you know, brethren; it is important we understand this.
The day you accept Jesus Christ as your Lord and personal Saviour,
the day you make a commitment to Jesus, you have declared war against satan.
This means war.
By identifying yourself with Christ, you have made satan your bitter enemy.
Becoming a Christian is basically making yourself a mark, a target for satan to shoot at.
He hates you the way he hates Jesus.
That is the meaning of our Christian journey.
That is why our journey as Christians, our road to the throne is not a bed of roses.
It's not just easy; it's not rosy.
We have loss and gain. We experience ups and downs, highs and lows.
We experience social, moral and economic uncertainties.
We harbour internal and external troubles.
The road to the Kingdom of God is not just a bed of roses because satan is looking for a way to strike.
Looking for an avenue to hit, to penetrate.
And God knows this.
Look at the case of Job.
With God's permission, you can be tempted.
Temptation can come in any form, at anytime, from anyone; temptation can come.
If God is aware of it, if God has knowledge of it, if God allows it,
you can be tempted just like Job.
Don't think it strange and doubt your Guard.
No, you can be attacked but you can never be destroyed.
I hope you are listening to what I am saying, people of God.
As a Christian, you can be attacked but you can never be destroyed.
Satan is never permitted to block our way without the providence of God making a way out.
If satan today brings iron to block your way,
look left, look right, look back, look front, you don't see any way out,
God will bring a welder to cut a way out through the iron.
1 Corinthians 10:13:
"No temptation has overtaken you except such as is common to man;
but God is faithful and He will not allow you to be tempted beyond what you can bear
but with it, will provide a way out."
In fact, if we are on God's agenda, in line with God's will, God's Word,
often the very things that seem an abortion of God's plan are actually the road to it's fulfillment.
What you look at as the end, with Christ, it will open the door to new beginnings.
But the problem lies when you step out of your way, out of your duty, out of God’s agenda.
Then you forfeit His promise and put yourselves out of God’s protection.
The promise of God that says, "I will be with you.
Even though you walk through the valley of the shadow of death, you will fear no evil for I will be with you".
When you step out of God's will, out of God's agenda,
you forfeit the promise and you are on your own.
Our natural strength cannot defeat satan in battle.
When you tempt the devil to tempt you,
you provoke God to withdraw His strength and leave you to your own strength.
Tell your neighbour, "Don't tempt the devil to tempt you".
Now I want to try and use an illustration to gain great understanding of this principle.
And for this illustration, I need three volunteers, male volunteers.
Oh, there we go, three straight, Thank you very much, brethren.
The language I want to use to demonstrate this example is a language that is universal.
The language of football.
Where are you from, sir?
From Lagos.
Nigeria.
Akwa Ibom.
From Spain.
Wow, we have a bit of a world cup here.
Now, brother from Spain, if you come with me.
We are going to split ourselves into two teams.
Just turn around and face the crowd, sir.
This is Team Jesus.
Here is Team Satan.
Very sorry, brother; just for now, just for a moment.
We want to have a very quick exercise that will help illustrate this principle of what it means
when you tempt the devil to tempt you.
Ok, so this is our playing ground. This is our ball.
All of us have played some street football before, especially the men.
Irrespective of where you are from - we all know how to play football on the streets.
Alright, so let's make the goal a little bit bigger, a little bit easier.
So the aim of this game is very simple.
I and my brother here - Team Jesus - we want to score in this goal.
Team Satan wants to score in this goal.
I think the easiest way to do this is with a whistle.
Another rule I forgot to tell you.
I am playing in this game but I'm also explaining the sermon.
So any time you hear this whistle, pause.
Are you ready?
Crowd, I hope you are going to support Team Jesus.
If we see people cheering for Team Satan, don't worry - we will pray for you later for your deliverance.
Come, my brother. Ok. Three, two, one - go.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Ok, the ball is with Team Satan. Come on, Team Satan, let's see if we can...
I see skills.
Ok, no problem.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We got the ball again.
Oh, look at that. Come on!
Yes!
Goal!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Brilliant! Alright.
Don't worry, the example is still coming. We have to score a goal first.
1:0 Team Jesus. Ok, come on then guys, let's go.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Yeah, this guy is good.
Ok, now watch this.
Hold on.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What just happened?
Team Satan is my enemy, my adversary, my opponent but I just gave him the ball.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I just gave him the ball. We are on the opposite side.
I gave him the ball and don't be surprised if he strikes.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
He scored! Why did Team Satan score?
Why?
Why do you complain when satan strikes when you are the one that gives him the ball?
Each time you go where Jesus is not welcomed, you give him the ball.
Each time you listen to what you know is corruptive and destructive to your spirit,
you give him the ball.
Each time you as a married man ask for a phone number from that lady you met,
Each time you are on your computer, your laptop, your phone and a pornographic advert comes up,
which says, "Click here to see more" and you look to your left, look to your right and click,
you give him the ball.
Each time you put a password on your phone that even your wife doesn't know
because what you are doing on there, you don't even want your own wife to know what you are doing,
you give satan the ball.
Don't be surprised when he strikes.
Don't be surprised if he scores because he is a very good attacker.
He is a very good striker.
Don't tempt the devil to tempt you.
Do you know what we as people of God are supposed to do? I will tell you what.
We are not even supposed to be playing games with Team Satan.
We are children of God - what is our business with them?
When we see that they have come into our heart, do you know what you are supposed to do?
Out! Go!
Send them out.
Give them a red card. Send him out.
You have no business with him.
When you send him out of the way, there is no way - you can score.
But today, many of us, what we do, we give satan just a yellow card.
"I will give you another chance, satan. I will give you a warning. Let's try again."
You give him a yellow card, instead of you to take your position in the believer's authority,
'You satan, you have no business in my life, my family, my marriage, my career. Get out!"
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It was a good game so we have to compensate our brethren.
I think Team Jesus won 2:1.
Please come and take an altar fruit as a blessing for your life.
We will not give you a red card on the altar. Don't worry.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
No mortal man or devil can supersede the plan of God for your life.
There is only one person who can get you out of the will of God - and that is you.
That is you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
One of the greatest gifts God has given us is the freedom to make decisions.
All of us who have fallen made a decision
and all of us who have not fallen faced a similar temptation and made a different decision.
It is not our challenges, temptations, troubles that make us fall;
it is our reaction to them.
While some of us yield to the pressure and make wrong decisions,
others face the same pressure and make the right decisions.
Whoever you yield yourself to obey, that is whose servant you are.
Romans 6:16.
Brethren, our heart is a treasury.
Luke 6:45 says that a good man brings forth good things out of the good that is stored up in his heart
but an evil man brings forth evil things out of the evil stored up in his heart.
What are you storing up in your heart?
Pride or humility?
Love or hatred?
Offence or forgiveness?
What you store up in your heart will be revealed at the point of temptation.
Temptation provokes what you are hiding, what you are storing.
What you have been keeping in your heart provokes that temptation.
That your weakness comes out in the face of temptation.
What you have been keeping, hiding, harbouring in your heart.
Look at Judas Iscariot in the Bible - the betrayer.
Judas Iscariot lived and walked with Jesus
He was one of the twelve that Jesus sent out to heal the sick and deliver the demon-possessed.
He heard the teachings, he saw the miracles, he lived with Jesus.
But the Bible says in John 12:4-6 that Judas Iscariot harboured the secret sin of stealing.
He took from the money bag when no one was looking.
What he harboured in his heart gave satan a foothold to enter
and manipulate him to the point of betraying the Son of God.
Cain - you know the story of Cain and Abel in the Bible.
Let's quickly turn there; turn to the Book of Genesis.
Genesis 4:7.
You know, Cain gave an unworthy offering -
an offering to honour himself and dishonour God.
God was not happy; God told him in that Genesis 4:7,
"If you do what is right, will you not be accepted?
But if you do not do what is right, sin is crouching at your door;
it desires to have you but you must rule over it."
Even with this warning from God, because Cain bore a grudge against his brother Abel,
because God accepted Abel's offering,
satan had a foothold in his heart and manipulated him to the point of murdering his own brother.
On the contrary, Joseph - we know the story of Joseph.
Do you know the reason why Joseph did not succumb to the temptation from Potiphar's wife?
Potiphar's wife was trying to seduce Joseph, wanted to sleep with him at all cost.
Do you know the reason why Joseph did not give in or yield or submit to that temptation?
He knew who he was; he was a child with a promise of God.
I tell you today - you are children of promise.
You are children of destiny.
You are children with a promise from God.
Your destiny does not permit you to give your heart to fleshly desires.
Your destiny, your promise from God is too precious to be corrupted, tainted, perverted.
Your destiny does not permit you.
Consider your destiny.
Your destiny does not allow you to waste time on things that have no lasting value and significance.
Your destiny does not permit you to strive and struggle against flesh and blood.
Consider your destiny.
Be God conscious.
Cultivate a consciousness of God.
If you are conscious of God, your heart will not rest until it rests in Him.
You go where Jesus will not be welcomed -
your spirit will be agitated until you leave that place.
You have a conversation with someone and you sense a satanic influence - you will quickly cut it off.
But today, the problem is that satan's traps for us are often hidden.
He would disguise himself as an angel of light and come with his hidden agenda.
It takes the grace, the strength of one grounded in the Word of God,
to be able to identify the devil's tricks for what they are.
If you ask any man here, "Will you sleep with a snake?",
he will say, "No, over my dead body!"
Satan knows that so he will put a spirit of snake inside a beautiful lady.
By the time you meet them, it's not just your bodies that meet; it's your spirits.
No physical protection can withstand spiritual contamination.
Many destinies have been diverted, many homes broken, many lives shattered
because we've given our hearts away to fleshly desires.
I'm coming to a conclusion, brethren, but I want to tell you something that happened to me;
how God used Prophet T.B. Joshua to preserve my life.
When I came here to The SCOAN as a visitor, many many years ago;
I was in the prayer line, I was about 14-15 years old.
Prophet T.B. Joshua walked up to me and gave me a word of prophecy.
He walked up, looked at me and said," Young man, there is a lady that you are close to,
and you have to be very careful because she is demon-possessed".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I didn't do that on the outside.
You know when you receive a prophecy, you say, "Yes, Man of God, it's true".
But within me, I was like, "Ah! What? There is a lady close to me that is possessed?"
In fact, I began to think, "Maybe it is this one. Oh my God, what is happening?"
You should have seen me when I got back to UK.
If a lady came close to me, "Be gone from me, you satan!"
I quickly gave her the red card because I was so scared that someone would come.
This is Prophet T.B. Joshua who had told me; I didn't know who the person was.
But that prophecy preserved me from making a stupid mistake.
As a young man, you know the temptations that we face -
peer pressure, temptations up and down, here and there.
Anytime this temptation would come, I would remember what the Prophet had told me,
"There is a lady that is close to you. She is demon-possessed".
"Ay! Ok, I’m gone! Goodbye. Thank you."
Leave the place just like Joseph. Get out.
When Joseph was tempted, he didn't just stay there; he got out.
Tell your neighbour, "Get out before sin gets in".
If you ask Samson, he will tell you - a night of pleasure is not worth a lifetime of blindness.
In conclusion, brethren:
The truth of this sermon is enough to change your life.
But don't just listen to this sermon; study the sermon of your own life.
Your life experience will testify to this truth.
Poison is poison, irrespective of how it is packaged.
Please, don't tempt the devil to tempt you.
Life already has enough challenges.
You are a Christian; you have declared war against satan.
There are already enough challenges in life for you to create one for yourself -
to create your own trouble, challenge, temptation.
Jesus said to His disciples, "I pray your faith will not fail".
It means He knew situations would come that would test them, tempt them
and try to remove them from their faith
but He said, "I pray your faith will not fail".
This means, our faith may fail but not fall off.
If faith is kept up in the hour of temptation, though we are cast down, we will not be utterly destroyed.
And if God allows it, it will not lead to our end, to our downfall.
It will lead to our promotion.
Just stay in line with the will of God.
And He is there to see you through whatever life brings.
May God bless His Word in the midst of our hearts, in Jesus' name.
TT Monica Asefa 27/12/18
RV: Mel Flowers 03/01/2019